freightos.com 2019-06-14

# Freightos Privacy Policy | Freightos

_Effective May 25, 2018_

Freightos’ mission is to make global trade frictionless by bringing logistics providers, importers, exporters and carriers online, making international freight easy and transparent. Similarly, it’s important to us that we are transparent about the data we collect about Freightos users (aka you) and how we use that data.

This Privacy Policy applies when you use Freightos and our websites. We offer our users choices about the data we collect, use and share as described in this Privacy Policy, Settings and our [Help Center](http://resources.freightos.com/).

## Introduction

Freightos operates a suite of web applications to support digital freight sales, booking, and management for logistics professionals. Our Privacy Policy applies to any Visitor or User of Freightos.

Our registered users and website visitors use Freightos to compare freight shipping options, educate themselves with regards to freight processes or current market conditions, book and pay for their shipments, manage them, and coordinate and communicate with their respective logistics providers. This involves sharing information regarding shipment routes, cargo details, and business information about themselves and their logistics needs and services.

### Services

This Privacy Policy, including our Cookie Policy set out below in Section 6, applies to your use of our Services.

This Privacy Policy applies to freightos.com, Freightos-branded apps, Freightos Market Intelligence services and other Freightos-related sites, apps, communications and services (“Services”), including off-site Services, such as our freight support staff, but excluding services that state that they are offered under a different privacy policy, like our suite of software-as-a-service solutions for providers, carriers, and supply chain companies.

Data Controllers and Contracting Parties

Freightos Limited, a Hong Kong company, will be the controller of your personal data provided to, or collected by or for, or processed in connection with our Services;

As a Freightos Visitor or Buyer, the collection, use and sharing of your personal business data is subject to this Privacy Policy (which includes our Cookie Policy and other documents referenced in this Privacy Policy) and updates.

### Change

This Privacy Policy apply to your use of our Services on or after the date in the header.

Freightos (“we” or “us”) can modify this Privacy Policy (although we try not to do that often), and if we make material changes to it, we will provide notice through our Services, or by other means, to provide you the opportunity to review the changes before they become effective. If you object to any changes, you may [close your account here.](https://meetfreightos.typeform.com/to/QFWcBk)

You acknowledge that your continued use of our Services after we publish or send a notice about our changes to this Privacy Policy means that the collection, use and sharing of your personal data is subject to the updated Privacy Policy.

## 1\. Data We Collect

### 1.1 Data You Provide To Us

You provide data to create an account with us.

#### Registration

To create an account you need to provide data including your company name, email address, some information about your shipping habits such as frequency, mobile number, and a password. Upon booking a shipment, you also provide a payment method. In some cases, you may invite additional users to access your account; we retain this data as well. We will collect data about your location country and preferences such as language.

#### Searches

You search for freight quotes, book them and upload relevant commercial details to process the shipment.

When you search for a shipment, we retain the parameters that you searched for. We also retain information about shipments booked, phone calls conducted regarding that search, on-site and emailed messages with both our team and the selected logistics provider, as well as payment information. For shipments to take place, you’ll also frequently need to upload commercial documents, like your commercial invoice, power of attorney, hazardous material statements and other shipment-related documentation. These documents in turn may contain other personal or business data. We use this information to help streamline your shipments and they are only accessible to relevant Freightos employees and the relevant service provider.

#### Posting and Uploading

We collect data from you when you provide, post or upload it to our Services, or when you communicate with Freightos staff or your service providers or your buyers by phone, email, chat, or our in-app messenger. You almost never have to post or upload personal data, as Freightos is a commercial platform and in general we recommend using business email address, phone number, address where possible for transacting on Freightos.

1.2 Data From Others

Customers and partners may provide data to us.

#### Partners

We may receive data about your company when you use the services of Freightos providers and partners, such as insurance agencies, customs brokerages, logistics providers, and credit score assessment companies. If you provided any of our partners with relevant personal data, they may share it with us if deemed relevant.

### 1.3 Service Use

We log your visits and use of our Services.

We log usage data when you visit or otherwise use our Services, including our sites and platform technology, such as when you view or click on web pages or freight quotes, perform a search, or engage with our content. We use log-ins, cookies, device information and internet protocol (“IP”) addresses to identify you and log your use.

### 1.4 Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

We collect data through cookies and similar technologies.

We use cookies and similar technologies (e.g. pixels, ad tags and device identifiers) to recognize you and/or your device(s) on, off and across different Services and devices. We also allow some others to use cookies as described in our Cookie Policy below. You can control cookies through your browser settings and other tools. Our website and our services are intended for business users (freight is not typically a popular personal hobby).

### 1.5 Your Device and Location

We (indirectly) receive data from your devices and networks, including location data through third-party technology.

When you visit or leave our Services (including our plugins or similar technology on the sites of others), we receive the URL of the site you came from. Our third party technologies also may get information about your IP address, proxy server, operating system, web browser, device identifier and features, and/or ISP. For specific, location-related tools, we will ask you to opt-in before we use GPS or other tools to identify your precise location.

### 1.6 Messages

If you communicate through our Services, we learn about that. It’s supposed to work that way and would be weird if we didn’t.

We collect information about your messages when you send, receive, or engage with messages in connection with our Services. We also use automatic scanning technology on messages (which is kind of cool, if you think about it).

### 1.7 Information Provided from Freight Partners/Employers

When your employer or shipping partner uses Freightos services and invites you to the platform, they give us data about you.

If an employer or business partner (supplier, customer, handling agent, customer broker etc.) invites you to collaborate on Freightos, they may provide us with business data about you and your company. For example, they may share your company name, role at the company, contact details, and permissions levels when you manage their shipments. Again we recommend using business contact details where possible.

### 1.8 Other

Your freight shouldn’t stand still. Neither does our development.

Freightos often introduces new features to make freight tick, like live shipment tracking. If we collect materially different personal data or materially change how we use your data, we will notify you and may also modify this Privacy Policy.

## 2\. How We Use Your Data

We use your data to provide, support, personalize and develop our Services.

We use the data that we have about your business account to provide and personalize our services, including with the help of automated systems and inferences we make, our services so that they can be more relevant and useful to your company.

### 2.1 Services

Our Services help your company optimize freight shipping and make global logistics easier with access to global service providers, freight quotes, shipment management, educational material and more.

### 2.2 Communications

Communication is what make freight shipping work. Freightos helps your company communicate with our support staff and with our service providers. This takes places through both in-app and offline channels (and as few faxes as possible).

We will contact your business through email, phone, or messages on our websites, and other ways through our Services, including text messages and push notifications. To keep you in the loop, we’ll also use these channels to let you know about the availability of our Services, security, and other service-related issues. Like the rest of the internet, we also send messages about how to use Freightos, reminders that hopefully help you save time and money on freight, and promotional messages from us and partners that we like. You may change your communication preferences at any time [here](https://www.freightos.com/contact-us/). There are some notifications we can’t let you opt out of, like service messages from us, including security and legal notices.

We also enable communications between you and others through our Services, including our in-app messenger and emails.

### 2.3 Marketing

We promote our Services to you and others.

We use data and content about how businesses use Freightos to promote our digital freight revolution. For example, we may use the logos or names of really cool companies that have shipped with us. We never share personal information, without running it by you first.

### 2.4 Research

We develop our Services and conduct research.

#### Service Development and Freight Research

Freight traditionally lacks transparency and Big Data. We’re incredibly proud of building a tool that empowers business users with data they need… but it involves conducting research on platform engagement, freight shipping patterns and more, to help disseminate freight knowledge back to our users.

We also use engagement patterns with our platform to help optimize product development. If a lot of users (or one very important one, just like you) seem to like a feature, we’re going to double down on that. The user business data that we have or collect informs us and helps us further develop our platform. In some cases, we work with trusted third parties to perform this research while taking measures to protect individual business privacy.

### 2.5 Customer Support

We use data to help you fix problems.

We use the data (which can include your communications) to investigate, respond to and resolve complaints and Service issues (e.g., bugs). Hopefully, you’ll never need to figure that out.

### 2.6 Aggregate Insights

We use data to generate aggregate insights.

We use your data to produce and share aggregated insights that do not identify you.  For example we may use your data to generate statistics about the businesses using Freightos or for creating aggregate freight indices and other market insights. We always anonymize data for these insights.

### 2.7 Security and Investigations

We use data for security, fraud prevention and investigations.

We use your data (including your communications) if we think it’s necessary for security purposes or to investigate possible fraud or other violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy and/or attempts to harm our members or visitors.

## 3\. How We Share Information

### 3.1 Our Platform

Any shipment-related data is shared with the relevant internal Freightos employees, as well as the service providers you’ve selected.

#### Shipment Communications

Information communicated within Freightos is shared using our internal communication platforms, such as the in-app messenger, or through normal digital channels like email or phone. We never ask people to fax us documents though and if a company does, you should encourage them to get with the program.

#### Shipment Documentation

Shipment documents are stored on Freightos, where they can be accessed by the relevant internal Freightos employees or external service providers. When these documents need to be conveyed to external parties, we will typically use digital communication platforms like email or our application.

### 3.2 Communication Archival

Regulated users may need to store communications outside of our Service.

Some Freightos users (or their employers) need, for legal or professional compliance, to archive their communications and social media activity, and will use services of others to provide these archival services.

### 3.3 Related Services

We share your data across our different Services and Freightos entities.

Freightos entities, like our subsidiaries offices around the world, may share your business data internally to provide and develop our Services. We may combine information internally across the different Services covered by this Privacy Policy to be more relevant and useful to you and others.

### 3.4 Service Providers

We use others to help us with our Services.

We use others to help us provide our Services (e.g., maintenance, analysis, audit, payments, fraud detection, marketing and development). They will have access to your information as reasonably necessary to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for other purposes. If you’ve already read this far, it shows that you’re pretty diligent. So take our word for it that we’re also very diligent and ensure that our partners treat your data with the respect it deserves.

### 3.5 Legal Disclosures

We may need to share your data when we believe it’s required by law or to help protect the rights and safety of you, us or others.

It is possible that we will need to disclose information about you when required by law, subpoena, or other legal process or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (1) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies; (2) enforce our agreements with you, (3) investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, (4) protect the security or integrity of our Service (such as by sharing with companies facing similar threats); or (5) exercise or protect the rights and safety of Freightos, our users, personnel, or others. We attempt to notify Members about legal demands for their personal data when appropriate in our judgment, unless prohibited by law or court order or when the request is an emergency. We may dispute such demands when we believe, in our discretion, that the requests are overbroad, vague or lack proper authority, but we do not promise to challenge every demand.

### 3.6 Change in Control or Sale

We may share your data if our business is sold to others, but it must continue to be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We can also share your personal data as part of a sale, merger or change in control, or in preparation for any of these events. Any other entity which buys us or part of our business will have the right to continue to use your data, but only in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy unless you agree otherwise.

## 4\. Your Choices & Obligations

### 4.1 Data Retention

We keep most of your personal data for as long as your account is open.

We retain your personal data while your account is in existence or as needed to provide you Services. This includes data you or others provided to us and data generated or inferred from your use of our Services. Even if you only use our Services when searching for freight quotes every once in a while, we will retain your information and keep your profile open until you decide to close your account. In some cases we choose to retain certain information in a depersonalized or aggregated form.

### 4.2 Rights to Access and Control Your Personal Data

You can access or delete your personal data. You have many choices about how your data is collected, used and shared.

We provide many choices about the collection, use and sharing of your data, including opt-outs and communication controls. For personal data that we have about you:

  * Delete Data: You can delete personal data from your profile page or ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data (e.g., if it is no longer necessary to provide Services to you) through this [link](https://meetfreightos.typeform.com/to/QFWcBk).
  * Change or Correct Data: You can edit some of your personal data through your account. You can also ask us to change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if it’s inaccurate.
  * Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (e.g., if we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (e.g., if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held).
  * Right to Access and/or Take Your Data: You can ask us for a copy of your personal data and can ask for a copy of personal data you provided in machine readable form.

You may contact us using the contact information below, and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.

### 4.3 Account Closure

We keep some of your data even after you close your account.

If you choose to close your Freightos account, your personal data will generally stop being visible to others on our Services within 24 hours. We generally delete closed account information within 30 days of account closure, except as noted below.

We retain your data even after you have closed your account if reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations (including law enforcement requests), meet regulatory requirements (including financial regulations and FMC), resolve disputes, maintain security, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our Terms of Use, or fulfill your request to “unsubscribe” from further messages from us. We will retain de-personalized information after your account has been closed.

Information you have shared with others will remain visible after you closed your account or deleted the information from your own profile or mailbox, and we do not control data that other Members copied out of our Services.

Note for example that in some cases your name, email, or phone may appear on freight quotes and contracts which we will keep indefinitely for regulatory reasons, or for the integrity of our financial records, even after you stop being a User.

## 5\. Other Important Information

### 5.1. Security

We monitor for and try to prevent security breaches. Please use the security features available through our Services.

We implement security safeguards designed to protect your data, such as enforcing the use of HTTPS. We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks. However, we cannot warrant the security of any information that you send us. There is no guarantee that data may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

### 5.2. Cross-Border Data Transfers

We store and use your data outside your country.

Countries where we process data may have laws which are different, and potentially not as protective, as the laws of your own country. At this time most  of our data is stored in the US.

### 5.3 Lawful Bases for Processing

We have lawful bases to collect, use and share data about you. You choose to use our Services and have choices about our use of your data.

At any time, you can withdraw whichever optional consent you have provided by requesting to withdraw.

We will only collect and process personal data about you where we have lawful bases. Lawful bases include consent (where you have given consent), contract (where processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you (e.g. to deliver the Freightos Services you have requested)) and legitimate interests. Legitimate interests will include processing your personal data for the purposes of Freightos legitimate interests or for the legitimate interests of third parties (e.g., your employer or company), provided that such processing shall not outweigh your rights and freedoms. For example, we may process your personal data to:

  1. Protect you, us, or others from threats (such as security threats or fraud)
  2. Comply with laws that apply to us
  3. Enable or administer our business,Manage corporate transactions, such as mergers or acquisitions
  4. Understand and improve our business or customer relationships generally

Where we rely on your consent to process personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time and where we rely on legitimate interests, you have the right to object.  

## 6\.  Freightos Cookies Policy

This section describes use of cookies and other technologies.

6.1 What are cookies and other technologies?  
A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer, mobile phone, or other device when you visit a website. The cookie helps website providers recognise your device the next time you visit their website (so, for example, you don’t need to log-in every time you check out Facebook). There are other similar technologies such as pixel tags (transparent graphic images placed on a web page or in an email, which indicate that a page or email has been viewed), web bugs (similar to pixel tags), and web storage, which are used in desktop software or mobile devices.

There are also technologies such as mobile device identifiers and SDK integrations to help companies recognise your device when you return to an app or otherwise use Freightos  services.  
6.2 How we use cookies and other technologies

We use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your device for a set period of time or until you delete them). We use the following types of cookies for the purposes explained in this chart:

Cookie Type| Purpose  
---|---  
Essential Operational| These cookies are necessary to allow us to operate the Freightos Service as you have requested. For example, they let us recognise if you have an existing account to make sure you can log in and stay logged in.  
Performance / Analytics| We use these cookies to analyse how the Freightos Service is accessed, is used, or is performing. We use this information to maintain, operate, and continually improve the Freightos Service. We may also obtain information from our email newsletters, including whether you opened or forwarded a newsletter or clicked on any of its content. This information tells us about our newsletters’ effectiveness and helps us ensure that we’re delivering information that you find interesting.  
Functional| These cookies let us operate certain functions of the Freightos Service in line with the choices you make. These cookies mean that when you continue to use or come back to the Freightos Service, we can provide you with our services as you have asked for them to be provided, such as knowing your username, remembering how you have customised our services, help ensure you get the right marketing material when you download content, and reminding you of content you have enjoyed.  
Targeting / advertising| We use these cookies to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests. The information may also be used for frequency capping purposes (e.g., to ensure we do not display the same advertisement to you repeatedly) and to help us regulate the advertisements you receive and measure their effectiveness.  
Freightos Ads| We work with web publishers, advertising networks, and service providers to deliver Freightos ads on other web sites and services. Cookies may be used to serve you with Freightos advertisements and to regulate the advertisements you receive and measure their effectiveness.  
  
We also use mobile device identifiers and the other technologies for the purposes articulated in this Privacy Policy, for example to recognise your device when you return to the Freightos app or otherwise use the Freightos Services.

### 6.3 Manage your cookie and other preferences

Many web browsers allow you to manage your preferences. You can set your browser to refuse cookies or delete certain cookies. You may be able to manage other technologies in the same way that you manage cookies using your browser’s preferences. In addition, when you visit the Freightos corporate homepage for the first time, you will be informed that these cookies are in place and that by continuing your web session, you consent to these cookies being used.  
Please note that if you choose to block cookies with your browser or other tools, it may impair the Freightos Service or prevent certain elements of it from functioning.  
There is no accepted standard on how to respond to Do Not Track signals, and we do not respond to such signals.

An available tool is the Network Advertising Initiative’s (NAI) Opt-Out Tool at [networkadvertising.org/choices](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). This allows you to opt out from the use of information about your online activities for online behavioral advertising by NAI member companies.

On your mobile device, you may also have a “Limit Ad Tracking” setting (on iOS devices) or a setting to “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads” (on Android) which allows you to limit the use of information about your use of apps for purposes of serving ads targeted to your interests.

One of the services we use to track activity related to the Service, e.g., by placing cookies, is Google Analytics by Google (Google, Inc. a company headquartered at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). We may use vendors, including Google, who use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform and optimise, our Services based on your past visits to our websites, including Google Analytics for Display Advertising. Google provides tools to manage the collection and use of certain information by Google Analytics at tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and by Google Analytics for Display Advertising or the Google Display Network by using Google’s Ads Settings at google.com/settings/ads.

You hereby consent to the use of the cookies and other technologies described above.

## Contact Information

You can contact us or use other options to resolve any complaints.

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Policy, please contact Freightos [here](https://www.freightos.com/contact-us/).

Thanks for trusting Freightos with your business and your data.
